ABRAR HASAN

Mirpur-13, Dhaka

PERSONAL PHONE No: +8801403061198 ALTERNATIVE PHONE No: +8801521584145

E-MAIL: abrarhasan1998@gmail.com
(GITHUB: https://github.com/abrarhasan3)

YOUTUBE: youtube.com/@abrarhasan4197

LINKEDIN: linkedin.com/in/abrarhasan3/



Objective

I am an experienced Lecturer and Program Coordinator with teaching and academic leadership experience at Daffodil International University and Green University of Bangladesh. I am passionate about creating an engaging learning environment and helping students achieve academic and personal growth. Beyond academics, I have served as President of the KUET Debating Society, where I developed strong leadership and public speaking skills, and I actively manage an educational YouTube channel to make learning accessible and enjoyable. With a commitment to student success and academic excellence, I aim to contribute meaningfully to shaping future professionals and advancing the academic community.

Education

MSc. in Computer Science and Engineering Bangladesh University of Engineering & Technology (BUET)	2024-Current
BSc. in Computer Science and Engineering Khulna University of Engineering & Technology (KUET) CGPA: 3.64 out of 4.00	2019-2024
Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC) Notre Dame College, Dhaka GPA: 5.00 out of 5.00	2016-2018
Secondary School Certificate (SSC) Dinajpur Zila School, Dinajpur GPA: 5.00 out of 5.00	2014-2016

Publications

Journal:

"A Lightweight Cryptographic Framework Based on Hybrid Cellular Automata for IoT Applications." IEEE Access, vol. 12, pp. 192672-192688, 2024, doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3519673

Abrar Hasan, M.M.A. Hashem

Teaching Experience

1.	Lecturer, Dept. of Software Engineering Green University of Bangladesh	September, 2024 - Current
2.	Lecturer (Contractual) Dept. of Software Engineering Daffodil International University	July,2024 – September,2024

Administrative Experience

Program Co-Ordinator

Dept. of Software Engineering Green University of Bangladesh

September, 2024 - Current

Scholarships & Awards

Dean's Award Dean's award from The Honorable Dean of Faculty of Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE), KUET for excellent results.	2022
Dean's Award Dean's award from The Honorable Dean of Faculty of Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE), KUET for excellent results.	2021
Dean's Award Dean's award from The Honorable Dean of Faculty of Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE), KUET for excellent results.	2020
Champion Freshers League 2019 Freshers' League is one of the most prestigious tournaments arranged by KUET Debating Society.	2019
Government Scholarship, HSC Government Scholarship in HSC examination is awarded for Excellent result.	2018
Government Scholarship, SSC Talent-pool Scholarship the SSC examination is awarded for Excellent result.	2016
Regional Champion, Anti-Corruption Commission – Bangladesh Debate Anticorruption debate is a prestigious debate organized by Anti-Corruption Commission I participated from Dinajpur Zila School Team 1 and became champion.	2015
Quarterfinalist Bangladesh Television Interschool Debate I participated the competition from Dinajpur Zila School Debate Team -1 and qualified for the quarterfinals among the teams across the country.	2015

Thesis

A Study on Lightweight Cryptography Framework Based on Cellular Automata for IoT Applications.

Academic Project

Safe Road	YOLOv4 Android Application
-----------	------------------------------

This is a two-part project. An Android app is utilized in the first section for monitoring, route adjustment, and vehicle tracking. A traffic sign detector trained with YoloV4 makes up the second portion.

Modified Checkers Game

Python | AI | Minmax Algorithm

An AI based multiplayer game. Build with Pygame framework and minmax algorithm.

Mini Compiler Flex | Bison | C

A compiler designed to transform a custom language code into C program and execute it.

<u>Tuition Finder</u> Swift | IOS

An IOS application for the students and teachers for finding a tutor and apply for tuition.

Stock Database Oracle | Database

Developed a stock market database project using Oracle 10G Express Edition. Implemented several SQL queries for finding information. For example, analyzing maximum price holdings, profits, losses, and owner information etc.

<u>Cardiac Recorder</u>

Android | Java | Firebase

Cardiac Recorder is a simple, useful and user-friendly android application to monitor a person's heart rate, BMI and blood pressure

Railway Station Design

Graphics | OpenGL 3.3

A model rail station was designed using OpenGL 3.3.

Water level Detector and Automatic Irrigation Tools

Arduino | Sensor

This project is made with Sensors, Motors and Arduino to make an automated system for Irrigation and auto water tank filling.

Stock Value Finder Android | Java

This application was developed in android Studio Platform to fetch stock price of renowned companies.

Language Proficiency

proficient in Bangla and English

Extra-Curricular Activities

President 2023-2024

KUET Debating Society

Organized many workshops, intra-university and national tournaments (KUET IV 2023) for

the university level students.

President 2015-2016

Science Club, Dinajpur Zila School

Organized science fairs, Training sessions and workshops.

General Secretary 2015-2016

Debate Club, Dinajpur Zila School

Was active in both Debate and Organizing sessions and workshops.

General Secretary 2015-2016

Debate Club, Dinajpur Zila School

Organized various sessions, workshops.

Competitive Programming

CODEFORCES

Solved 364 problems with 1024 contest rating.

Reference

Dr. M.M.A. Hashem

Professor

Department of Computer Science and Engineering Khulna University of Engineering & Technology,

Khulna -9203, Bangladesh

E-Mail: hashem@cse.kuet.ac.bd

Website: http://www.kuet.ac.bd/cse/hashem/

Phone no: +8801714003949

Dr. K. M. Azharul Hasan

Professor

Department of Computer Science and Engineering Khulna University of Engineering & Technology,

Khulna -9203, Bangladesh E-Mail: az@cse.kuet.ac.bd

Website: https://www.kuet.ac.bd/cse/azhasan/

Phone no: +8801714087273